Harrison's Flowers is a drama, romance, war film directed by Élie Chouraqui.
Harrison Lloyd, a renowned photojournalist covering the
war in Yugoslavia, is reported missing.
Sarah, his wife, convinced that he is not dead,
decides to go to Bosnia to find him.
Sarah Lloyd, played by Andie MacDowell.
Yeager Pollack, played by Elias Koteas.
Marc Stevenson, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Kyle Morris, played by Adrien Brody.
Harrison Lloyd, played by David Strathairn.
Margaux Lloyd, played by Quinn Shephard.
Harrison's Flowers (French: Les Fleurs d'Harrison) is a 2000
war-romance drama film directed by Elie Chouraqui.
It stars, among others, Andie MacDowell, Elias Koteas, Brendan Gleeson, Adrien
Brody, Marie Trintignant, Gerard Butler and David Strathairn.
The film is also Quinn Shephard's big screen debut.
The film premiered at the 2000 San Sebastián International Film Festival,
and released in theatres on 24 January 2001 in France.
Universal Pictures gave the film a limited theatrical release in the United States on 15 March
2002, then Lionsgate released this film in the United States on DVD in 2007.
For this film's United States version, the film's length was reduced by about
5 minutes; it also features a new score by Cliff Eidelman.
The film only grossed $3 million in worldwide box office against $8 million
production budget, and the overall critical reaction to the film was mixed.
However, Adrien Brody said that this film helped him to be cast in the leading role of
The Pianist (2002), for which he won the Academy Award for Best Actor.
Kino Lorber Studio Classics released the film for the
first time on Blu-ray on November 26, 2024.
There is a factual error in this film: the character played by Adrien Brody says that
Croats are Orthodox and Serbs are Catholic, without being contradicted.
The film explores themes of war crimes, balkan war, genocide, missing person.
The tone is emotional.